动物园
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
presisco
特效
压制
SG
我现在在哪?
Where am I now?
爸爸?
Dad?
史蒂文?
Huh? Steven?
爸爸,是你!
Dad, it's you!
史蒂文!我的小子!
Steven! My little man!
爸爸!
Dad!
当蓝钻石抓走你时,我担心死了
When Blue Diamond took you, I got so scared.
然后宝石人们说你可能
And then the Gems said you might be in
在那种非常恐怖的人类动物园里,被锁链束缚在墙边
some horrible human zoo all chained up to a wall
为了为了点花生而出丑
doing tricks for peanuts.
嘿,嘿,没什么,崽子
Hey, hey, it's okay, schtu-ball.
你的老爸好得很
Your old man's perfectly fine.
等等,你们是怎么来到这的?
Wait, how'd you even get out here?
我们在地球上有艘宝石人的太空飞船
We got on a Gem ship from Earth.
我会在回家的路上详细跟你说
I'll tell you about it on the way home.
我和宝石人们分开了
I got separated from the Gems.
我们得找到她们并救你出去
We got to find them and bust you out of here.
其实,从那里是出不去的
Well, you're not gonna get out that way.
我已经试过了
I've already tried.
什么?
What?
那么,如果我们去找的话总会有条路的
Well, there might be another way out if we can find it.
嘎雷格!
Ga-reg!
跟你在一起的是谁?
Who is that with you?
他是新朋友吗,嘎雷格?
Is this a new friend, Ga-reg?
Y6,J10,他是-
Wy-Six, Jay-Ten, this is --
老爸是我的!
Let me have my dad back already!
嘿,别这样,放松点
Hey, don't be like that. Relax.
这些人在我来之后对我一直非常好
These people have treated me so well since I got here.
什么?
Wha?
你好,你好
Greetings, greetings.
你好,嘎雷格
-Wow. -Hello, Ga-reg.
喔,一个新的小朋友-嘎雷格
-Wow, a new small friend. -Ga-reg.
大家听着,这是史蒂文
Everyone, this is Steven.
他是我儿子
He's my son.
呃,嗨
Uh, hi.
嗨
Hi.
谢谢你们给我爸爸梳辫子
Thanks for braiding my dad's hair.
史蒂文,这些人是那些
Steven, these people are the descendants of humans
几千年前被宝石人带来的人类的后代
brought here by Gems thousands of years ago.
他们从没见过地球
They've never seen the Earth before.
这听起来很疯狂吧?
Isn't that wild?
史蒂梵,嘎雷格讲过你的故事
Ste-van, Ga-reg has told stories of you.
"薯条渣,薯条渣!"
"The bits, the bits!"
那是你,对吧?
That's you, right?
薯条渣,薯条渣,薯条渣!
The bits, the bits, the bits!
来啊,一起喊啊
Come on, say it.
咱们走吧
Let's get out of here.
我们之前见到了一扇连接着动物园的门
We came across a door that leads into the zoo,
但是我们从外面打不开
but we couldn't open it from the other side.
让我们找到并试着开启它吧
Let's find it and try to open it from in here.
一扇门?真的?
A door? Really?
好吧,咱们今晚找找看
All right. Let's find it tonight.
这会容易一些,如果是在"日常"后的话
It'll be easier to look for it after the routine.
大家好
Greeting, everyone.
是时候开始"日常任务"了
It's time to start the daily routine.
请在指定的用餐时间享用你的大餐!
Please enjoy your meal during this designated eating period.
那是谁?
Who was that?
史蒂梵不知道微语音是什么
Ste-van does not know what a little voice is.
就像嘎雷格刚来时一样
Just like Ga-reg when he first arrived.
我们的微语音指引我们在这里的生活
Our little voices guide us through life here.
你们现在肯定都饿了
You all must be hungry now.
-是的-我们都是
-Yes, yes. -We are.
呃,爸爸?
Um, Dad?
别担心,史蒂文,我们会离开这里的
Don't worry, Steven. We'll get out of here.
但现在,让我们先融入这里
But for now, let's just play along.
给你,嘎雷格
Here you go, Ga-reg.
哦,谢谢
Oh, thank you.
史蒂梵,今天的水果是紫色的
Ste-van, today the fruit is purple.
你们喜欢食物吗?
Are you enjoying the food?
噢,是的
Oh, yes.
食物怎么样?好吃吗?
How is the food? Is it good?
当然,非常美味
Yes. It is delicious.
现在该玩耍了
Now it's time to play.
现在,每个人,将手伸出,就像你能
Now, everyone, reach up like you're going
触碰到太空
to touch outer space.
就是这样
That's it.
伸的高些
Reach up high.
这很有趣吧?
Wasn't that fun?
从昨天到现在我还没这么开心过
I have not had that much fun since yesterday!
现在该停下闻一闻花朵了
It's time to stop and smell the flowers.
如果我不想闻花朵呢?
What if I don't want to smell the flowers?
你为什么不想这么做呢?
Why wouldn't you want to do that?
该洗漱了,所有人
Time to clean up, everyone.
让我们洗个清爽的澡吧
Let's all take a refreshing bath.
看我的水花,嘎雷格!
Watch my splash, Ga-reg!
不错!
Nice one!
嘎雷格,看我的!
Ga-reg, watch mine!
那是我见过的最小的水花
Those are the tiniest splashes I've ever seen.
看这个
Watch this.
嘿,Y6,你听说过入水炮弹吗?
Hey, Wy-Six, - you ever heard of a cannonball?
从来没听过
I've never heard it.
跟我说说呗
Tell me what it is.
看这个
Check this out.
我会表演给你看
I'll show you.
入水炮弹!
Cannonball!
-入水炮弹!-入水炮弹!
-Cannonball! -Cannonball!
你们很喜欢在泳池中清洁自己吧?
Wouldn't you like to clean off in the pool?
好吧
All right, all right.
入水炮弹!
Yeah! Cannonball!
嘿,你还好吗?
Hey, you hanging in there?
我没法理解,他们都那么开心
I can't believe this. They're all so happy.
就好像他们不知道自己被困在这里一样
It's like they don't even know that they're trapped here.
其实,他们当然不知道
Well, of course they don't.
他们没去过其他地方
They've never been anywhere else.
他们喜欢在这里,我是指,你看看这个地方
They love it here. - I mean, look at this place.
你能怪他们吗?
Can you blame them?
他们有所需的一切
They've got everything they need,
而且不需要为任何事担心
and they never have to worry about a thing.
我觉得你是对的
I guess you're right.
Hmm?
现在该"晚安"了
And now it's time to say good night.
晚安,各位
Good night, everyone.
睡个好觉
Sweet dreams. -
天哪,划了一天水居然还累了
Geez, I sure am tired from doing a whole lot of nothing.
那么,晚安,崽子
Well, good night, schtu-ball.
爸爸,现在是我们逃出去的时候
Dad. Now's our chance to get out.
天,微语音真的让我
Man, little voice has really got me
接受了动物园人的作息时间了
on that zooman sleep schedule.
哦
Oh.
这是...
Is that...
这是大门
It's the door.
好,那么我们该怎么打开它呢?
Great. How do we get it open?
嘎雷格!
Ga-reg!
哦!
Oh!
史蒂梵!
Ste-van!
蛤?
Huh?
原来是你们制造的噪音
So you're the ones making the noise.
你们在做什么?
What are you doing?
这是个游戏吗?
Is it a game?
我们能一起玩吗?
Can we play, too?
这不是游戏
It's not a game.
我们得想方法让门打开
We need to get this door open.
"门"是什么?
What is a door?
就是,墙的一部分,但能开
Like, this part of the wall but open.
墙不会开
Walls don't open.
墙就是墙
They're walls.
有个关于会开的墙的故事
There is a story of an opening wall.
很久以前,一个宝石人从墙洞走进来
A very long time a go, a Gem came through a wall hole
帮助一个受伤的人
to help someone who was hurt.
你说的"受伤"指什么?
What do you mean hurt?
我不知道,我不知道什么叫"受伤"
I don't know. I don't know what hurt is.
我知道"受伤"!
I know what hurt is!
你知道?
You do?
呃,就像你感觉很难受
Um, it's like when you feel bad.
难受?
Bad?
对,就像,好的对立面
Yes, like, the opposite of good.
如果那是唯一的方法,那么,爸爸
If that's the only way out, then, Dad,
狠狠的打我脸吧
slug me in the face.
什么?!我才不会打你呢!
What?! I'm not gonna hit you!
这是我们的出路
It's our ticket out of here.
我们中的一个得受伤
One of us has to get hurt.
好吧,那么,你打我吧
Okay, well, then you hit me.
你确定?
You sure?
当然,我愿意为团队挨揍
Yeah. I'll take one for the team.
来吧,让我看看你怎么样
Come on, give me all you got.
我能承受的
I can take it.
入水炮弹!
Cannonball!
呃,怎么样?
Uh, how was that?
可以
Good.
有人来吗?
Anyone coming?
看起来不像
Doesn't look like it.
我该再试一次吗?
Should I try it again?
如果再来一次,就没什么需要解救了
There won't be anything left to rescue if you do.
我们现在该怎么办?
What do we do now?
看她说什么了
Whatever she says.
现在是"天选"的时候了
It is time for the choosening.
请在"天选"的圈子处集合
Please gather around the circle of choosening.
史蒂梵,嘎雷格,"天选"马上就要开始了
Ste-van, Ga-reg, the choosening will start soon.
跟我们去吧,总算-总算要来了!
Come with us. It's -- it's finally time!
嘎雷格,跟我们一起走到圈子里
Ga-reg, step into the circle with us.
这是某人的生日吗?
Is it somebody's birthday?
史蒂梵,在这里等着,直到"天选"结束
Ste-van, wait here until the choosening is complete.
"天选"对我们是非常特别的活动
The choosening is a very special event to us.
我们很高兴在这么好的时刻你能来
We're glad to have you with us at such a wonderful time.
很高兴来这里
Glad to be here.
让"天选"开始吧
Let the choosening begin.
U12,请站到圈子的中央
U12, please step into the center of the circle.
F3...哈?
-F3... -Huh?
请站到圈子中央
...please step into the center of the circle.
你们已经被"天选"为一对了
You have been choosened for each other.
等等
Wait a second.
这不是强行配对吗?
Is this some kind of matchmaking thing?!
这类乌托邦总有漏洞
There's always a catch to these utopias.
嘎雷格,不管是谁被"天选"给你,都非常幸运
Ga-reg, whoever is choosen for you will be very lucky.
J10,请站到圈子中央
Jay-Ten, please step into the center of the circle.
哦,天哪
Oh, boy.
史蒂文,帮帮我
Steven, help me.
别担心,爸爸
Don't worry, Dad.
你是新来的,也许你不会被"天选"
You're new here, so maybe you won't get choosened.
对啊
Right.
嘎雷格
Ga-reg.
请站到圈子中央
Please step into the center of the circle.
等等,也许这是个意外
Hold on, maybe there's been a mistake.
嘎雷格,J10在等你啊
Ga-reg, Jay-Ten is waiting for you.
我能看出来发生什么了
I see what is going on here.
你确定?
You do?
你只是害羞啦!
You are just shy!
呃?
Huh?
别担心
Do not worry about it.
现在请接触对方的手
Now touch hands.
等等!在地球上不是这样的!
Hold on! This isn't how it works on Earth!
我不想被告知我和谁是"天选"的
I don't want to be told who to be choosened with.
嘎雷格,这毫无道理
Ga-reg, this makes no sense.
为什么你不想被"天选"?
Why wouldn't you want to be choosened?
你看,在地球上,就没有语音
Look, back on Earth, there was no voice
告诉你该跟谁在一起
to tell you who to be with.
这是你自己的选择
It was your own decision.
我母亲和父亲走到一起
My mom and dad didn't get together
并不是因为有人告诉他们如此
because someone told them to.
他们花时间了解对方并坠入爱河
They spent time getting to know one another and fell in love.
他们"天选"了对方,因为这是他们自己的选择
They choosened each other 'cause that's what they choosed.
嗯,我知道了
Hmm, I see.
如果在地球上是这样,那么...
If that's how it's done on Earth, then...
我选择嘎雷格
I choose Ga-reg.
我也选择嘎雷格!
And I also choose Ga-reg.
等等!
Wait!
我也得说句话
I get a say in this, too.
你们都非常好,而且我很荣幸,而且是的
You're all very nice, and I'm flattered, and yes,
你们可以选择任何想要的人,
you get to choose whoever you want,
但我也得说我选择
but I also get to say that I choose
呃...不是你们中的任何一个
um...none of you.
喔!嘿,别哭啊
Whoa! Hey, don't cry.
你们可以选择其他人
You can choose someone else.
我感觉不好
I feel not good.
我感觉很糟
I feel bad.
这就是-就是受伤吗?
Could this be -- is this hurt?
为什么嘎雷格要伤害我们?
Why would Ga-reg hurt us?
将伤害带走吧
Take this hurt away.
我"天选"带着我爸逃跑
I choosen to take my dad and run away.
看着点那个-呕!
Watch out for that -- oof!
我从还有所有头发开始就没伤过这么多人的心
I haven't broken this many hearts since I had all my hair.
嘿,快回来
Hey, get back here.
这真是疯了
This is nuts.
赶快下来吧!
Just come down!
让我们谈谈
Let's talk about it.
我再也不会"天选"了!
I'll never choosen again!
当然你会的
Sure you will.
嘿,那扇门还开着
Hey, that door's still open.
这可能是我们唯一的机会了
This might be our only chance.
哦,不,别妄想了
Oh, no, you don't.
放我们下来!
Put us down!
你们两个麻烦大了
You two are in big trouble.